<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>fish on darlin.io</title><link>https://darlin.io/tags/fish/</link><description>Recent content in fish on darlin.io</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 08:13:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://darlin.io/tags/fish/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>shortcut for using docker contexts</title><link>https://darlin.io/posts/docker-context-shortcut/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 08:13:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://darlin.io/posts/docker-context-shortcut/</guid><description>As cool as docker contexts are, I kept running into an issue: I would forget to switch contexts before running a command. I wanted to be able to run docker commands as normal, but have them automatically use the correct context.
I decided to devise a solution consisting of convention and my existing tools:
I name my directories containing docker-compose.yml manifests after the context they are intended for. I use command substitution when executing docker commands, so that I can use the current directory name to determine the context.</description></item><item><title>a fish shell abbreviation that sparks joy</title><link>https://darlin.io/posts/docker-fish-abbreviations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 May 2021 21:09:58 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://darlin.io/posts/docker-fish-abbreviations/</guid><description>summary My favorite command line shell is fish, and one feature I find especially useful is abbreviations.
Abbreviations are essentially text-expanded shortcuts. Continue reading for a quick rundown.
basic usage To add an abbreviation simply call abbr -a WORD EXPANSION, where WORD is the abbreviation and EXPANSION is the expanded command. For example: abbr -a gco git commit.
To use it, simply type gco, followed by Space or Enter.
advantages Abbreviations can be very useful because:</description></item></channel></rss>